Lothar Wolff collection, 1926-1987
George Eastman Museum
- Series 8, Film/Video, 1943-1953; 1960-1961; 1966-1986; undated
  - Subseries 8,The World We Live In, 1968-1973
    - The Sun, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1393:0001
    - Survival in the Sea, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1388:0001
    - Water, Old Problems New Approaches, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1350:0001
      Accession No.: 1989:1351:0001
    - The Winners, 1968
      Accession No.: 1989:1389:0001
  - Subseries 9, Features and Other Non-series Films, 1953; 1961; 1978-1986; undated
    - The Joy of Bach-- Short Version, 1978
      Accession No.: 1989:1328:0001
    - The Joy of Bach-- Long Version, 1978
      16mm print, 2 reels
      Accession No.: 1989:1329:0001
    - Louise Brooks, 1986
      3/4" U-matic videocassette master positive
      Accession No.: 1987:0794:0001
    - Martin Luther, 1953
      Accession No.: 1989:1330:0001
    - Question 7, 1961
      16mm print, 3 reels
      Accession No.: 1989:1457:0001
    - The Sky's the Limit, 1984
      Accession No.: 1989:1327:0001
    - The Solar System, 1980
      Accession No.: 1989:1363:0001
    - Stars, Galaxies and the Southern Skies, undated
      Accession No.: 1989:1361:0001
    - The Sun: The Earth's Star, 1980
      Accession No.: 1989:1362:0001
- Series 9, Artwork, approximately 1960-1987; undated
  Consisting of 24 folders and artifacts, this series features conceptual work and related correspondence for a variety of film and television projects. In this case artwork refers to drawings, collages, illustrations, paintings, and transparencies, as well as reference pieces taken from publications. The bulk of the series covers the date range of 1980-1983, with ca. 1960 and 1987 outlier dates. However, the majority of the series is undated.
  Series contains artwork from such completed productions as The Sky’s the Limit( 1983 ) and proposed productions like The 13 Clocks( ca. 1962 ), as well as images of the solar system. The artwork for The 13 Clocks was done by animator Philip Stapp. In many cases the project for which these pieces were created remains unknown. Series also contains a number of undated Czech animation cells. The provenance of this material and its connection to Wolff is unknown.
  Materials are housed in two boxes.
  - no title (Box OS-1)
    - The Sky’s the Limit-- Photo Material, ca. 1984 (Folder 1)
    - [Ballooning artwork and clippings], ca. 1984 (Folder 2)
      Photos and illustrations, some with marked-up transparent paper overlays indicating camera movement.
    - [Ballooning artwork], ca. 1984 (Folder 3)
    - [Ballooning and solar system artwork], ca. 1984 (Folder 4)
      Colored reproduction of engraving depicting French peasants destroying a hot-air balloon, with tissue overlay; fragments of acetate, possibly illustrating the solar system.
    - [The 13 Clocks, earth and moon artwork;Life Around Us], ca. 1960; ca. 1970; undated (Folder 5)
      Large promotional brochure for Life Around Us TV series; paintings for The 13 Clocks by Philip Stapp; photos and artwork depicting the earth and moon.
    - [Ballooning artwork and The Sky’s the Limit title screen], ca. 1984 (Folder 6)
    - [Ballooning artwork], ca. 1984; undated (Folder 7)
    - ["Bachanalia" advertisement], undated (Folder 8)
    - [Ballooning and Solar System Artwork, Clippings, and Invoices], undated (Folder 9)
      Reproductions of a hot-air balloon engraving; a painting of a Venusian landscape by Luděk Pešek; and photographs, woodcuts, and engravings of astronomical subjects. Some illustrations have transparent paper overlays indicating camera movement. Folder also includes handwritten shot list, a transparency from Flight of the Prisms, and copy service invoices.
    - [Ballooning Artwork], undated (Folder 10)
    - [Ballooning artwork], ca. 1984 (Folder 12)
    - [Moon artwork], undated (Folder 14)
      Photographs and reproductions of artwork featuring the moon.
    - ["Moon Phases" folder], undated (Folder 15)
      Large folder labeled "National Geographic -- Moon Phases" containing artwork featuring sequential phases of the moon, some with transparent paper overlay with camera instructions.
  - no title (Box OS-2)
    - [National Geographic Artwork\, undated (Folder 1)
      Folder originally labeled "Oversize Lothar Wolff Collection." Contains a folder labeled "National Geographic" (made out of board) containing artwork and transparencies depicting the solar system.
    - [Czechoslovakian animation cels], undated (Folder 2)
      Painted animation cels featuring a butterfly, a young girl, and a bird. Along with the cels in Box OS-2, Folder 3, these materials are of uncertain provenance and may not be part of the Lothar Wolff Collection.
    - [Czechoslovakian animation cels], undated (Folder 3)
      Painted animation cels featuring a bird carrying a rabbit andS grass background. Along with the cels in Box OS-2, Folder 2, these materials are of uncertain provenance and may not be part of the Lothar Wolff Collection.
    - [Artwork], undated (Folder 4)
      Two painted maps (Europe and Italy).
    - [Astronomy artwork], undated (Folder 5)
      Cardboard inscribed with circles and geometric figure; black-and-white photograph of observatory with color-gel overlays; color transparency of Saturn labeled "Saturn #1" and mounted between boards with transparent paper overlay; yellow engraving of sun mounted on glossy board with painted stars and animation instructions on reverse, labeled "Mercury Background"; glossy board with three white painted spheres; reproduction of German diagram depicting planets' solar orbits, with transparent paper overlay and camera instructions.
    - [Envelope labeled "Lothar Wolf Prod. – Artwork of ‘Voyage through Space’ – Cataloged 4-28-87 UA"], 1964; 1979-1980; 1987 (Folder 6)
    - [Envelope labeled "Bach Artwork – Cataloged 4-28-87 UA"], ca. 1979 (Folder 7)
- Series 10, Awards/Citations, 1953; 1961-1966; 1971-1972; 1980-1982
  Consisting of 27 items, this series is composed of awards and notices of nomination in the forms of statues, plaques, and certificates. The series covers the dates 1961-1966, 1971-1972, and 1980-1982, with one award circa 1953.
  These awards and citations were given to a variety of film and television productions that Lothar Wolff was involved with, including The Joy of Bach( 1980 ) and Question 7( 1961 ). Also included in this series is an Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences Certificate of Nomination for Award for Fortress of Peace( 1965 ).
  TK
  - no title (Box C014)
    - Blue Ribbon Award for "Rock-a-Bye Baby" for Education Film Library Association of the American Film Festival, 1972 (Folder 25)
  - no title (Box C019)
    - [California Federation of Women’s Clubs Motion Picture Award for Question 7], 1961 (Folder 1)
    - [Southern California Motion Picture Council Inc. certificate for Fortress of Peace], 1966 (Folder 2)
    - [CINE 1971 certificate for Martin Luther Excerpt] (Folder 3)
    - [CINE 1971 certificate for "How Old Is Old?"/Life Around Us] (Folder 4)
    - [11th Berlin International Film Festival Award for Question 7], 1961
    - [Plaque, "Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences Certificate of Nomination for Award for Fortress of Peace"], 1965
  - no title (Box C019A)
    - [American Film Festival Blue Ribbon Award for "The Not-So-Solid Earth"], 1972
      Framed award certificate.
    - [Two American Film Festival Blue Ribbon Awards for "Rock-a-Bye Baby"], 1972
    - [Plaque for The Joy of Bach, U.S. Industrial Film Festival], 1982
    - [Plaque, awarded by Lutheran Brotherhood for The Joy of Bach], 1980
    - [National Education Film Festival Award for The Solar System], 1981
  - no title (Box C262)
    - [Two awards from the Office Catholique International du Cinema], undated
  - no title (Box C308)
    - Announcement of "Prize of the Public" in Besançon, France for the The Joy of Bach, 1981 (Folder 8)
  - no title (Box C352A)
    - [Educational Film Library Association-- American Film Festival blue ribbon], undated
      Blue ribbon embedded in clear plastic on marble and wood base. Plastic is detached from base. Awardee is not indicated.
  - no title (Box C352B)
    - [Interfilm Award], 1962
    - [American Film Festival Blue Ribbon Award for "The Not-So-Solid Earth"], 1972
    - [American Film Festival Blue Ribbon Award for "Rock-A-Bye Baby"], 1972
    - [American Film Festival Blue Ribbon Award for "Magnetic Force"], 1962
  - no title (Box C352C)
    - [10th Festival International de Cinema Nyon Certificate], 1978
    - [Chris Plaque Award for The Solar System], 1981
    - [Screen Writers’ Guild Nomination for Award for Martin Luther], ca. 1953
    - [Citation from IV Mostra Internacional do Film Cientifico, Rio de Janeiro], 1972
      Metal and glass framed citation to Lothar Wolff, June 1972.
    - [Hardcover book,The Promise of the Future], 1971 (Folder 1)
      Rockefeller University prospectus, inscribed "To Lothar Wolff, June 30, 1971, the Rockefeller University Press."
    - [8th Annual Landers Associates Award of Merit to The Not-So-Solid Earth], ca. 1972 (Folder 2)
  - no title (Box C356)
    - Misc. Photographs, 1947; 1967; 1974; undated (Folder 9)
      Front and back of a 1947 Festival Mondial du Film et des Beaux-Arts de Belgique plaque recognizing Storm over Britain; "M. Monaco" receiving an award from the Office Catholique International du Cinema.
  - no title (Box C368)
    - [Interfilm Award for Question 7], 1962 (Folder 18)
  - no title (Box OS-2)
    - [Framed CINE 1980 certificate awarded to The Joy of Bach] (Folder 8)